# N RISHI RAJ REDDY

phone: 6295612299 address: Visakhapatnam, Andhra Pradesh, 530026 github: github.com/rishirajreddy email:

rishirajreddy.07@gmail.com **Linkedin:** linkedin.com/in/rishi-

raj-reddy/
portfolio:

rishirajreddy.github.io/my\_port

folio/

# **ABOUT ME**

A full-stack developer with experience in the development and deployment of web applications. Skilled in both backend and front-end development using a variety of programming languages. Experienced in developing applications using **HTML**, **CSS** and **JavaScript**. Well-versed in multiple development framework and technologies like **Angular** and **NodeJS**. Familiar with tools like **GitHub** and version control like **GIT**.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Angular
- Bootstrap
- GitHub

- NodeJS
- ExpressJS
- MongoDB
- Firebase
- AWS
- Heroku
- GIT

### **EDUCATION**

2018 - 2022 | ANDHRA UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Technology, CSE

CGPA - 7.60

2015 - 2018 NANDALAL JALAN SHIKSHA SADAN, RANIGANJ

**Higher Secondary School** 

CGPA - 6.0

2014 - 2015 DAV PUBLIC SCHOOL, RANIGANJ

Secondary School

**CGPA - 7.5** 

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### WEB DEVELOPER INTERN

January 2021 - March 2021 | TOI Foundation

- Contributed to building responsive websites using HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript.
- Collaborated with web designers and back-end developers to create userfriendly web applications.
- Optimized web pages for maximum speed and compatibility across different browsers and devices

### BACKEND DEVELOPER INTERN

May 2021 - Jul 2021 | AI AND SMART TECHNOLOGIES

- Responsible for developing the back-end architecture and database design.
- Implemented various features using Node.js and Express.js. Optimized the application for performance and scalability.
- Managed the MongoDB database and oversaw data migrations

### **PROJECTS**

### INFINITY-GRAM

MEAN Stack (MongoDB, ExpressJS, Angular, NodeJS), AWS

- This project is purely made from MEAN stack. It's like a mini-instagram.
- In this web-app, user can create his/her profile, post pictures, like posts & also comment on posts.
- Angular is used for the frontend and MongoDB as the database.
- This web-app is deployed to AWS Elastic BeanStalk service.

☐ https://github.com/rishirajreddy/MEAN\_mini-insta-angular-frontend

#### MOVIES-DB

MEAN Stack(MongoDB, ExpressJS, Angular, NodeJS), AWS

- This project is also made from MEAN stack. Its a movies DB.
- This web-app is mainly focused on AWS S3 where the posters and trailers of the movies are fetched.
- MongoDB is used as the database to store the movie details.
- This web-app is deployed to AWS ElasticBeanstalk EC2 instance.

https://github.com/rishirajreddy/movied\_DB\_meanStack

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

• The Complete Web Development BootCamp 2021 Issued on April 2021 | Udemy

• The Complete Angular Guide 2022 Issued on March 2022 | Udemy